Alright, we're moving along in our sequence for insomnia.
Our next pose is downward facing dog.
Down dog is one of the most widely recognized yoga poses, and it's an all over rejuvenating stretch.
So what we're going to do is from our hero?s pose, we're going to place our hands shoulder width apart, come into a table top, tuck the toes under and exhale as we lift up.
We're going to lift through the hips, through the sitz bones, through the tailbone and we're going to drop the heels down to the floor.
So if you feel like you want to bend your knees, go ahead and bend your knees, but keep lifting the tailbone up, and keep this line from the wrist to the hip straight.
It's more important to keep that line straight, than it is to straighten the knees all the way.
So if you're here, you really want to be here and if that means you want to lift up on your toes, than lift up on your toes.
You can also peddle the feet one at a time, shifting through the hips.
While you're here, keep the palms flat on the floor, keep the fingers spread, keep the shoulder blades wide and inhale and exhale through the nose.
See if you can make it to ten breaths in down dog, and when you're done gently drop the knees and rest for a moment in Childs pose.